In the previous module we have seen a number of bootstrapped
在前面一些课里我们学习了一系列
components that are supported through the CSS classes.
通过 CSS 类来实现的 Bootstrap 组件
In this module we'll look at the Java script supported bootstrap components.
接下来我们将会学习 JavaScript 对 Bootstrap 组件的支持
All these components that we examine this module will require
所有我们接下来将要学习到的组件
a JavaScript plugin to be in place for them to work correctly.
都需要有 JavaScript 插件作为基础
As we have seen in the previous two modules,
正如我们已经学习过的
Bootstrap provides a rich set of CSS classes that can be applied to
Bootstrap 提供了很多 CSS 类 你可以通过在许多 HTML 元素上应用它们
many HTML elements in order to create the Bootstrap components.
来创建 Bootstrap 组件
These components, as we saw in the previous module,
事实上 仅仅通过应用一些 Bootstrap 类
are created by just applying the Bootstrap's CSS classes.
就可以创建这些非常棒的组件了
Now, you can use Bootstrap purely for its CSS classes and
但这样会有一个问题
completely ignore the JavaScript plugins and
那就是你将完全忽视掉 JavaScript 插件的强大功用
the JavaScript based components in Bootstrap.
以及一些基于 JavaScript 的 Bootstrap 组件
But let's also examine how we can make use of the Java Script
那么接下来就让我们学习如何应用
based components in Bootstrap in this module.
Bootstrap 的基于 JavaScript 的组件
As we saw in the previous module, CSS classes for
正如我们已经学习过的 许多组件都是以
many components start with the base class, like for example the button class.
一个基础 CSS 类来作为最外层的封装的 比如说实现按钮时的 "class=btn"
Or from class or the table class and so on.
又或是实现表格时的 "class=form" 或者 "class=table"
But these classes can be further modified by applying
如果想要实现更多的效果 我们需要在这最外层封装的属性设置中
additional CSS classes that belong to the same group of classes.
加入其它一些 CSS 类别
As an example, let's look at the button class.
我们以按钮为例
We can create a simple button by just applying the btn class, but
如果单纯地应用 "class=btn" 那么就将会是一个最简单的按钮
we would want to further qualify it by giving it one of the standard colors.
如果想要设置颜色的话 就需要诸如 "class=btn-default" 这样的设置了
Perhaps even specify the size of the class.
又或是想要设置大小的话 就是 btn-xs 之类的
And also whether it should be a block button or not.
我们甚至能够设置其 block 属性 亦即设置其是否填充整行
So all these additional classes that belong to the button
总结起来 就是在 btn 这个基类之后
group of classes act as modifiers to the button base class.
我们还能根据我们的需要来增添一些 其它用来修饰的类
Similarly, we have seen the nav class before, which was applied to URL and
类似的还有我们学过的 nav 类
for creating a component within the nav bar.
它用于创建导航栏中的组件
Be applied to the UL, the nav, and then the navbar-nav class too.
它也有诸如 navbar-nav 这样的用于修饰的类
In this module, we'll examine the nav class again, but here,
在本节课中 我们将会重新学习这个 nav 类
we will apply the nav-tabs and the nav-pills class to create
不过我们这次将主要学习 nav-tabs 和 nav-pills 类的使用
different kinds of navigational elements.
它们能够创建出一些不同的有意思的导航元件
Now, let's talk about Bootstrap's JavaScript plugins themselves.
那么 让我们先谈谈 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 插件 本身是什么东西
Bootstrap's JavaScript support comes through a set of JavaScript plugins.
事实上 JavaScript 对 Bootstrap 的支持 就是通过各种 JavaScript 插件来完成的
These plugins are built upon Jquery, so Bootstrap's JavaScript
这些插件是建立在 jQuery 上的 所以要想让这些插件发挥作用的话
competence depend upon Jquery to be present within your picture.
你需要引入 jQuery
That is the reason why, when we include in the Bootstraps,
那也是为什么当我们引入 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件时
JS competence, we also include a Jquery under the pitch.
我们同时引入了 jQuery
The plugins themselves have designs such that you can only include
这些插件都被设计得足够独立 这意味着一般来说你只需要引入
those plugins that you really need.
你需要的那些插件
If you want to include all the plugins, that is also feasible.
当然一下子引入所有插件也是可行的
This graphic may help you to better understand the view of JavaScript,
这张图可能可以给你
JQuery, and Bootstrap's components.
JavaScript, jQuery 和 Bootstrap 组件之间关系 的一个直观理解
If you look at JavaScript as the big heavy Sumo wrestler.
如果你把 JavaScript 看成是一个巨大的相扑选手
Then JQuery is a condensed version of the sumo wrestler,
那么 jQuery 就是一个压缩版的相扑选手
more easier to handle, so to speak, than the full JavaScript.
比起 JavaScript, 使用它会更加容易
Because the JQuery library plugins that come in,
因为有许多有趣的 jQuery 组件能够在
are very very useful to achieve many interesting aspects within your web page.
很多方面帮助到你的 web 开发
Now, what Bootstrap does is goes one more step further, and
至于 Bootstrap 则还多做了一步
then builds upon JQuery plugins, and then boxes them in.
它将一些 jQuery 插件封装了起来 你可以理解成将它们装进了一个小盒子
Into tiny little components which can be used on their own.
从而可以单独地方便地使用它们
You will pretty soon realize that you can use the Bootstrap's components without
你应该很快就能发现你可以 在一行 JavaScript 代码也不写的情况下
writing a single line of JavaScript code.
使用 Bootstrap 的相关组件
That's the advantage that you get with Bootstrap's JS components.
这也是使用 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件的 优势之一
But again, it comes with less flexibility,
不过相应的 这会使其灵活性大大降低
when you use it without writing JavaScript code.
毕竟一行代码都不写意味着难以定制
How do you include the Bootstrap's JavaScript plugins in your page?
那么怎么才能引用 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 插件呢
We've already seen that at the bottom of the page we would include these two
事实上我们已经在我们代码底部写了
statements to import that JQuery library,
引入 jQuery 库以及 Bootstrap 完整的 JavaScript 插件集
as well as the Bootstraps complete set of JavaScript plugins.
的两块代码
Now again, as I said, Bootstraps JavaScript components can be used without
我想再提一下的是 Bootstrap 的 JavaScript 组件
writing a single line of code.
可以在不写一行 JavaScript 代码的情况下使用
Now this is feasible because Bootstraps applies
这是因为 Bootstrap 有一系列
what they call is a first class API.
优先级很高的接口
With data-stash attributes, for
这些接口是通过 data-xxx 属性来接入的
example the data-toggle, the data-spy and so on.
其中 xxx 可以是 toggle, spy 之类的
Many attributes that Bootstrap JS components define.
Bootstrap JS 组件定义的属性
Now you can apply these attributes to
当你想在你的网页中使用这些组件时
the HTML elements that you use within your web page directly.
直接将相应的  HTML 元件的 class 设置为相应的属性即可
And without even writing a single line of JavaScript code,
然后你就可以在 不写一行 JavaScript 代码的情况下
the JavaScript components are ready to go for you.
使用相应的 JavaScript 组件了
Of course, they won't have the flexibility that
当然也正如我所提及的 这会使灵活性大大降低
you might get with directly writing JQuery code to control this components.
如果想要做更多的定制 则还是要写一些 jQuery 代码的
But much of the functionality is very much available
不过即使只用 data-xxx 属性
through the data star attributes.
也能实现很多功能了
This is the approach that we're gonna explore in this module.
而这也正是我们接下来要学习的
We look at them all full featured JavaScript API in the next module.
我们将会学习一套相当完备的 JavaScript 接口
In order for you to use the full fledged JavaScript API you need to be
它们将会帮助你比较全面地掌握 你需要掌握的 jQuery 语法
aware of the JQuery syntax and have enough knowledge of JavaScript.
以及 JavaScript 的相关知识 【翻译 - Carefree0910】